srisriravishankar.org 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy | Official Website of Sri Sri Ravi Shankar

This agreement is entered into by the Office of His Holiness Sri Sri Ravi Shankar on behalf of itself and its affiliates and licensors (“Organization”).

The Organization respects the privacy rights of visitors to our website and is committed to protecting those rights. To support this commitment, we have adopted a Privacy Policy that guides how we collect, use, disclose, update and protect the information you provide online to the Organization.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully before you use the Organization website. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected by Organization other than through its website.

Visitors to the Organization website from outside of the United States of America are advised that the Organization’s Privacy Policy is intended to meet the laws and requirements of the United States of America, which may not necessarily be the same as the laws and regulations of your home country. Any information that you provide to the Organization online will be handled in accordance with the laws and regulations of the United States of America.

 **Contents**

This Privacy Policy will inform you as to:

  * Which websites are covered by the Privacy Policy
  * What types of information (if any) may be collected from you and by what means
  * How such information may be used and shared
  * The consequences (if any) if you choose not to provide personal information
  * The measures that the Organization takes to maintain data security, quality and integrity
  * How you can confirm and, if necessary, change the personal information that the Organization maintains
  * Where and how to ask questions or file complaints

 **Websites covered by the Privacy Policy**

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to this website and other websites maintained by the Organization.  This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link.

When you click on a hyperlink displayed on our website, you may be leaving the Organization’s website and entering another website for which this Privacy Policy does not apply. You may not be specifically informed of this fact, although in most instances a new browser window will be opened when a hyperlink is redirecting you to a website which we do not operate or control. This may not always be the case, however. Therefore, before providing any personal information which may be requested from you, you should first verify the Uniform Resource Locator (URL) or the hypertext transfer protocol (http) address displayed by your web browser to confirm whether or not you are still accessing a website operated by the Organization. If not, this Privacy Policy will not apply to your visit.

You should carefully review the privacy statements or policies of any other website that you visit or wish to send email to because those privacy statements or policies will apply to your visit and email sent to that site and may be very different from the Organization’s Privacy Policy.

Our website is not intended for children under 18 years of age.  No one under age 18 may provide any personal information on our websites, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under age 18.  If you are under age 18, do not use or provide any information on this website, make any purchases through this website, use any interactive or public comment features of this website, or provide any information about yourself to us.  If we learn that we have collected or received personal information from a child under age 18 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information.  If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under age 18, please contact us at info@srisri.org.

 **Collection of Personal Information and Its Use and Purpose**

 ** _Data Storage and Transfer_**

Your personal data will be securely stored by and accessible to us, including our affiliated organisations and our technology outsourcing partners, on servers which may be located in countries with different data protection regulations than apply in your home country, for the purpose of providing information technology services on our behalf for the administration of the programs and offerings described on our website.   The data on the servers may also be accessed by us or our technology development outsourcing partners from outside your home country for system development and support purposes.

 ** _Electronic Marketing_**

By accepting our privacy policy, you agree that your personal data may also be made available to our carefully selected partner organizations located within and outside your country of residence for the purpose of offering you information regarding products and services related to our programs and offerings, and that we may also directly inform you of such products and services when they become available in your country or anywhere else in the world.

If you decide you do not wish to be informed of related products or services in the future, you will be given the opportunity to be removed from our database in our communications, and may request to unsubscribe at any time by contacting us at info@srisri.org.

 ** _Demographic and Aggregate Information_**

In order to provide you with the best possible experience on our website, the Organization may also collect demographic and aggregate information from online visitors who access its websites.  “Demographic information” is anonymous information such as age, gender and geographic location.  “Aggregate information” is data about a group or category of services or users from which individual identities have been removed.  Demographic and aggregate information is not considered personal information, as it does not permit the identification of an individual.

 ** _User Comments and Email_** __

Our websites will sometimes invite users to provide us with their comments on our services or on certain programs. Users who wish to provide us with their comments will sometimes have the option of also providing us with their name and email address. We do not require users to provide us with such information, however. Comments provided to the Organization by users may be posted on our websites. Alongside such comments, we may also post the user’s first name and last initial as well as the city and province that this user has indicated he or she is from. However, we will take measures to prevent such postings from containing any personal information.

If an online form or an email submitted by a user contains personal information, we will only use such personal information to the extent necessary to respond to any comment or question from such user. We will limit access to such personal information and will keep such personal information in a secure system. Although most online forms and email messages submitted by users are deleted after we respond, in certain cases hard copies or data extracts may be kept on file. Any such copy or any such information, to the extent it is personal, will also be stored in a secure location.

 **Disclosure of Your Personal Information** ****

We may disclose demographic and aggregated information about our users and information that does not identify any individual.

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy:

  * To our subsidiaries and/or affiliates.
  * To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business and who are also bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only in accordance with applicable data protection laws for the purposes for which it is authorized under this Privacy Policy.
  * We contractually require these third parties to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which it is authorized under this Privacy Policy.
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
  * To enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of the Organization, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

 **Accessing and Correcting Your Personal Information**

You may send us an email at info@srisri.org to request access to, correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us. We cannot delete your personal information except by also deleting your user account. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.

 **Safeguards to Protect Your Personal Information**

The Organization maintains reasonable safeguards in an effort to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the personal information we collect. We also have implemented reasonable security measures in an effort to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Personal information collected by the Organization is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public (e.g., locked rooms), and access to that information is limited to employees who need the information to provide you with our products or services.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our website. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the website.

 **Cookies, Web Beacons and Log Files**

Some of our sites use cookies. Cookies are small text files placed on your hard drive when you visit a website. These files identify your computer and record your preferences and other data about your visit so that when you return to the site, the site knows who you are and can personalize your visit. The cookies used on our websites are not linked to any personal information about you.

We use cookies to collect information so that we can determine how to improve our websites by seeing which areas, features and products are most popular, to personalize the website and make recommendations based on products you have examined while visiting our website and to improve the website experience. As noted, the information collected by the cookies we use is not personal information, as it is not identifiable to you specifically. As technology advances and cookies provide more functionality, we expect to utilize them in different ways. If so, we will update this Privacy Policy to identify such new uses of cookies.

Most browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. You can disable cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent. However, some areas of our website may not function properly if you do so. There are many sources for additional information about Internet cookies, and we encourage anyone concerned about the use of cookies to do more research on the topic so you can make an informed decision about accepting them from any site.

The Organization also uses “web beacons” (also known as “web bugs,” “action tags,” “pixel trackers,” or “clear GIFs”), which are small, graphic images on a web page, web-based document or in an email message that are designed to allow us or a third party to collect certain information and monitor user activity on our sites. Web beacons are invisible to the user because they are typically very small (only 1-by-1 pixels) and have the same color as the background of the web page, document or email message. We may use web beacons to collect non-personal information such as the IP address of the computer that the web beacon is sent to, the URL of the page the web beacon comes from, and the time it was activated (such as when you view the web page, advertisement or email that contains the web beacon). Web beacons can be linked to personal information, but we do not use web beacons that link to personal information. We may permit third parties to place web beacons on our sites, but these web beacons are not linked to personal information either.

The Organization maintains log files, which contain Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses. An IP address is a numeric address that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. We do not link IP addresses to personal information. In general, we only use log files to monitor traffic on our websites and to troubleshoot technical problems. In the event of abuse, however, we may block certain IP addresses.

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to make changes in this Privacy Policy. If we make such changes, we will post the changes and change the date at the top of the policy. Please check back from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes in our privacy practices.

 **Where and how to ask questions or file complaints**

By providing information on this website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of such information such manner as set out in this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to the disclosure of such information to third parties in accordance with the terms hereof.

If you have any questions, complaints, or comments regarding this Privacy Policy, please send an email to the following address: info@srisri.org _._
